triathlon.org 2019-09-16

# Privacy Notice | Triathlon.org

## WHO WE ARE

* * *

This website, triathlon.org (the “Site”), and all personal information collected from users of this Site are owned solely by International Triathlon Union (ITU). In this Privacy Notice references to “we”, “us”, “our”, are references to International Triathlon Union (ITU).

You can contact us at [info@triathlon.org](mailto:info@triathlon.org).

International Triathlon Union HDQ (ITU)  
Maison du Sport International  
Av. de Rhodanie 54   
Lausanne CH -1007, Switzerland

Tel: + 41 21 614 60 30

**We take the privacy of all our users seriously and regularly review this privacy notice.**

## VISITORS TO OUR WEBSITE

* * *

#### What information do we collect from you?

When someone visits triathlon.org we use a third-party service, Google Analytics, to collect standard internet log information and details of visitor behaviour patterns. We do this to find out things such as the number of visitors to the various parts of the site. This information is only processed in a way which does not identify anyone. We do not make and do not allow Google to make, any attempt to find out the identities of those visiting our website. 

#### Search engine

Our website search engine is powered by Algolia. Queries and results are logged anonymously to improve our website and search functionality. No user-specific data is collected by either ITU or any third-party.

#### E-Newsletter

We use a third-party provider, Mailchimp, to deliver our e-newsletters. We gather statistics around email opening and clicks using industry standard technologies including clear gifs to help us monitor and improve our e-newsletter. For more information, please see Mailchimp’s privacy notice.

## CHILDREN’S PRIVACY

* * *

We do not provide services to children (under 16) or proactively collect their personal information. 

## TRIATHLON.ORG REGISTERED USERS

* * *

#### What information do we collect from you?

  * Name
  * Date of birth
  * Gender
  * Phone number
  * E-mail
  * Medical information for anti-doping and paratriathlon issues.
  * Whereabouts information for the purposes of anti-doping.
  * Payment details including bank accounts for paying prize money and developing grants and reinvestment of expenses.
  * Any other personal data that you choose to upload to or post on the platform, including social media, photographs, messages, hobbies and interests and other personal details.

#### Why do we collect this information?

In general, your data will be processed by the ITU for the fulfilment of the following purposes:

  * Management of your relationship with ITU.
  * Organization of services and events.
  * Management of requests and applications.
  * Sending newsletters and new features.
  * Conducting surveys.
  * Communication of your personal data to third-parties collaborators and sponsors.
  * Processing of data relating to own and third-party cookies to analyze anonymous browsing habits and improve services.
  * Carrying-out ITU’s anti-doping program.
  * Results management both in-competition and out-of-competition
  * Performance information from training camps and courses.
  * Results of education courses.

#### Who might we share your information with?

  * Event Organisers - your name, Date of birth, gender and/or disability for classification purposes.
  * WADA for anti-doping purposes.
  * Our API subscribers. Public facing information that we display on our site is available for our users.

#### What do we do with your information? 

Register your participation in our events, store results & rankings.  
Carry out ITU’s anti-doping program to ensure a clean sport. Read more on ITU’s Anti-Doping program and data collection here.  
Keep you up to date on relevant information according to your membership - event information/changes, rules etc.

#### How long do we keep hold of your information? 

As long as you are a registered user. You can request to delete your account at any time via [info@triathlon.org](mailto:info@triathlon.org).

#### How can I access the information you hold on me?

If you have a registered account you have view/access to all information ITU has on you. A private download link will be made available shortly on profile pages.  
You can also directly request from [info@triathlon.org](mailto:info@triathlon.org).   
Except as expressly stated in this Privacy Notice, we will not sell, share, trade or license your personal information to others without your express consent.

## TRIATHLONLIVE.TV REGISTERED USERS

* * *

TriathlonLive [Privacy Policy](https://www.triathlonlive.tv/privacy)  
TriathlonLive [Cookies Policy](https://www.triathlonlive.tv/cookies)

## MEDIA CENTRE REGISTERED USERS

* * *

#### What information do we collect from you?

Your name, email and company/publication.

#### Why do we collect this information?

To verify you as accredited/approved media and keep you updated on media releases.

#### Who might we share your information with?

We use a third-party service supplier Mailchimp for mail services.

#### What do we do with your information?

Keep you updated on media releases.

#### How long do we keep hold of your information?

As long as you are a registered user.   
You can request to delete your account at any time via [info@triathlon.org](mailto:info@triathlon.org).

#### How can I access the information you hold on me?

If you have a registered account you have access to all information ITU has on you.  
A private download link will be made available shortly on profile pages.  
A request can also be sent to [info@triathlon.org](mailto:info@triathlon.org)

## EDUCATION HUB REGISTERED USERS

* * *

#### What information do we collect from you?

To access the site, you will have an account created for, which will comprise the following basic personal information:  
• Name, email  
The following information is also likely to be recorded (depending on which course you are accessing):  
• Gender, Country, Confederation, Preferred language, Official passport first name (if different from the given first name)  
There are then optional pieces of personal information which a user can add/edit about themselves:  
• City/town, Timezone, Description, Picture  
There will then be course specific information, such as which courses have been attended (including where and when) and whether the course was passed or not.  
Within each course, certain personal information may be collected. For example within face to face courses, medical information is requested that is accessible to the tutors on that course only.

#### Why do we collect this information?

In general, your data will be processed by the ITU for the fulfilment of the following purposes:  
• Management of your learning on the various courses offered by the ITU.  
• Sending notifications via emails regarding course activity. A user can manage their preferences regarding which emails they wish to receive at any time.

#### Who might we share your information with?

Contractors of ITU (tutors, coaches etc) will be given access to your data should you be attending a course under their charge.

#### What do we do with your information?

Organization of services and events.  
Performance information from training camps and courses.   
Results of education courses.

#### How long do we keep hold of your information?

As long as you are a registered user. You can request to delete your account at any time via [info@triathlon.org](mailto:info@triathlon.org). Though this will not include course records which must be kept for validation purposes.

#### How can I access the information you hold on me?

A request can also be sent to [info@triathlon.org](mailto:info@triathlon.org).

## ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

* * *

#### Security

We take every precaution to protect your personal information. In addition, we have strict security protocols in place to protect our customer database from unauthorized access, improper use or disclosure, unauthorized modification, and unlawful destruction or accidental loss. We only allow access to the customer database when necessary, and then under strict guidelines as to what use may be made of such details. We may ask you for proof of identity before disclosing any personal information to you.

#### Surveys

We always aim to improve the services we offer. As a result, we may occasionally canvass our customers using surveys. Participation in surveys is voluntary, and you are under no obligation to reply to any survey you might receive from us. Should you choose to do so, we will treat the information you provide with the same high standard of care as all other customer information.

#### Competitions

Your participation on our Site may mean that we occasionally contact you with the opportunity to enter competitions. Entry to competitions is voluntary, and you are under no obligation to take up an invitation from us to enter. Should you choose to enter a competition, we will treat the information you provide with the same high standard of care as all other customer information.

#### Correcting and updating personal information

If your personal information changes, or if you believe that the personal data we hold about you is incorrect, you may ask us to correct or update the personal information held by us by sending an email to [info@triathlon.org](mailto:info@triathlon.org).

#### Your rights

You are entitled to request the following:

  * Export all of my personal data
  * Delete all of my personal data

#### Privacy support

If you have any enquiry or concern about our privacy notice, please email us at [info@triathlon.org](mailto:info@triathlon.org).
